In this video, we'll figure out
在这段视频中 我们将会找出
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
a slightly simpler way to
一种稍微简单一点的方法来
write the cost function than we have been using so far.
写代价函数 来替换我们现在用的方法
And we'll also figure out
同时我们还要弄清楚
how to apply gradient descent to fit
如何运用梯度下降法
the parameters of logistic regression.
来拟合出逻辑回归的参数
So by the end of this
因此 听了这节课
video you know how to
你就应该知道如何
implement a fully working version of logistic regression.
实现一个完整的逻辑回归算法
Here's our cost function for logistic regression.
这就是逻辑回归的代价函数
Our overall cost function
我们的整体代价函数
is 1 over M times sum
不同的训练样本
of the training set of the
假设函数 h(x) 对实际值 y(i) 进行预测
cost of making different
所得到的不同误差
predictions on the different examples
算出的 Cost 函数值
of labels Y I. And
并且这是我们之前
this is a cost for a single example that we worked out earlier.
算出来的一个单个样本的代价值
And I just want to remind
我只是想提醒你一下
you that for classification problems
对于分类问题
in our training and in fact
我们的训练集
even for examples known in
甚至其他不在训练集中的样本
our training set, Y is
y 的值总是等于0或1的
always equal to 0 or 1.
Right?
对吗？
That's sort of part of the
这就是
mathematical definition of Y.
y 的数学定义决定的
Because Y is either 0 or 1.
由于 y 是0或1
We'll be able to
我们就可以
come up with a simpler
想出一个简单的
way to write this cost function.
方式来写这个代价函数
And in particular, rather than writing
具体来说
out this cost function on two
为了避免把代价函数
separate lines with two separate
写成两行
cases for Y equals 1 and Y equals
避免分成 y=1 或 y=0 两种情况来写
0, I am going to show
我们要用一种方法
you a way take these
来把这两个式子
two lines and compress them into one equation.
合并成一个
And this will make it more convenient
这将使我们更方便地
to write out the cost function
写出代价函数
and derive gradient descent.
并推导出梯度下降
Concretely, we can write out the cost function as follows.
具体而言 我们可以如下写出代价函数
We'll say the cost of H
Cost(h(x), y) 可以写成
of X comma Y. I'm going
以下的形式
to write this as minus Y
-y log(h(x))- (1-y) log(1-h(x))
times log H of
X minus 1
-y log(h(x))- (1-y) log(1-h(x))
minus Y times log 1
minus H of X.
-y log(h(x))- (1-y) log(1-h(x))
And I'll show you in a
我马上就会给你演示
second that this expression, or
这个表达式或
this equation is an equivalent
等式与我们已经得出的
way or more compact way
代价函数的表达
of writing out this definition
是完全等效的
of the cost function that we had up here.
并且更加紧凑
Let's see why that's the case.
让我们来看看为什么会是这样
We know that there are only 2 possible cases.
我们知道有两种可能情况
Y must be 0 or 1.
y 必须是0或1
So let's suppose Y equals 1.
因此 我们假设 y 等于1
If Y is equal
如果 y 是等于
to 1 then this equation
那么这个等式
is saying that the cost
这个 Cost 值
is equal to.
是等于
Well if Y is equal to one, then this thing here is equal to one.
如果 y 等于1 那么这一项等于1
And one minus Y is going to be equal to zero, right?
1-y 将会等于零 对吧？
So if Y is equal
如果 y 等于1
to one, then one minus Y
那么 1-y
is one minus one, which is therefore zero.
就是1-1 也就是0
So the second term gets multiplied
因此第二项乘以0
by zero and goes away,
就被消去了
and we're left with only this
我们只留下了
first term which is Y
第一项 y倍的 log 项
times log, minus Y times
-y 乘以
log H of X. Y is
log(h(x)) y等于1
1 so that's equal to minus
因此就等于
log H of X.
-log(h(x))
And this equation is
这个等式
exactly what we have
正是我们在这里的
up here for if Y is equal to one.
y=1 的情况
The other case is if
另一种情况是
Y is equal to 0.
如果 y=0
And if that is
如果是这样的话
the case then, writing of
那么写出的
the cost function is saying that
Cost 函数就是这样的
if Y is equal to zero,
如果 y 是等于0
then this term here, will be equal to zero.
那么这一项就为0
Whereas 1 minus Y, if
而1-y 在y=0时
Y equals zero, would be
1-y 就是0
equal to 1, because 1 minus
因为1-y就是
Y becomes 1 minus 0,
1-0 所以
which is just equal to 1.
最后就等于1
And so the cost function
这样 Cost 函数
simplifies to just this last term here.
就简化为只有这最后一项
Right?
对吧？
Because the first term
因为第一项
over here gets multiplied by zero, and so it disappears.
在这里乘以零 所以它被消去了
So we're just left with this last
所以 我们只剩下最后的
term, which is minus
这一项 也就是
log, 1 minus H of
-log(1-h(x))
X. And you can
你可以证明
verify that this term here
这里的这一项
is just exactly what we had for when Y is equal to 0.
就是当y=0时的这一项
So this shows that this
因此这表明
definition for the cost is
这样定义的 Cost 函数
just a more compact way of
只是把这两个式子
taking both of these expressions,
写成一种更紧凑的形式
the cases Y equals 1 and
不需要分 y=1
Y equals 0, and writing
或 y=0 来写
them in one, in a
直接写在一起
more convenient form with just one line.
只用一行来表示
We can, therefore, write
这样我们就可以写出
all of our cost function for logistic regression as follows.
逻辑回归的代价函数如下
It is this
它是这样的
one of m of the sum
就是 1/m 乘以后面这个 Cost 函数
of this cost functions, and plugging
在这里放入之前
in the definition for the
定义好的 Cost 函数
cost that we worked out earlier, we end up with this.
这个函数就完成了
And we just brought the minus sign outside.
我们把负号放在外面
And why do we choose this particular cost function?
我们为什么要把代价函数写成这种形式
When it looks like there could be other cost functions that we could have chosen.
似乎我们也可以选择别的方法来写代价函数
Although I won't have time to
在这节课中我没有时间
go into great detail of this
来介绍有关这个问题的细节
in this course, this cost function
但我可以告诉你
can be derived from statistics using
这个式子是从统计学中的
the principle of maximum likelihood
极大似然法得来的
estimation, which is an
估计 统计学的思路是
idea statistics for how
如何为不同的模型
to efficiently find parameters data for different models.
有效地找出不同的参数
And it also has a nice property that it is convex.
同时它还有一个很好的性质 它是凸的
So this is the cost function
因此 这就是基本上
that, you know, essentially everyone uses
大部分人使用的
when putting Logistic Regression models.
逻辑回归代价函数
If we don't understand the terms
如果我们不理解这些项
I just say and you don't
如果你不知道
know what the principle of maximum
什么是极大似然估计
likelihood estimation is, don't worry about.
不用担心
There's just a deeper
这里只是一个更深入
rational and justification behind this
更合理的证明而已
particular cost function then I
在这节课中
have time to go into in this class.
我没有时间去仔细讲解
Given this cost function, in
根据这个代价函数
order to fit the parameters,
为了拟合出参数
what we're going to do then is
我们怎么办呢？
try to find the parameters theta that minimizes J of theta.
我们要试图找尽量让 J(θ) 取得最小值的参数 θ
So if we, you know, try to minimize this.
所以我们想要尽量减小这一项
This would give us some set of parameters theta.
这将我们将得到某个参数 θ
Finally, if we're given a new
最后 如??果我们给出一个新的样本
example with some set
假如某个特征 x
of features X. We can
then take the thetas that we
我们可以用拟合训练样本的参数 θ
fit our training set and output
来输出对假设的预测
our prediction as this, and
just to remind you the output
另外提醒你一下
of my hypothesis, I am
我们假设的输出
going to interpret as the
实际上就是这个概率值
probability that Y is equal to 1.
p(y=1|x;θ)
And this is given the
就是关于 x 以 θ 为参数
implement X and parameters by theta.
y=1 的概率
But think of this
你就把这个想成
as just my hypothesis is
我们的假设就是
estimating the probability that Y is equal to 1.
估计 y=1 的概率
So all that remains to
所以 接下来要做的事情
be done is figure out
就是弄清楚
how to actually minimize J
如何最大限度地
of theta as a function
最小化代价函数 J(θ)
of theta so we can actually
作为一个关于 θ 的函数
fit the parameters to our training set.
这样我们才能为训练集拟合出参数 θ
The way we're going to minimize the
最小化代价函数的方法
cost function is using gradient descent.
是使用梯度下降法(gradient descent)
Here's our cost function.
这是我们的代价函数
And if we want to minimize it as a function of theta.
如果我们要最小化这个关于 θ 的函数值
Here's our usual template for gradient descent.
这就是我们通常用的梯度下降法的模板
Where we repeatedly update each
我们要反复更新每个参数
parameter by taking updating
用这个式子来更新
it as itself minus a
就是用它自己减去
learning rate alpha times this derivative term.
学习率 α 乘以后面的微分项
If you know some calculus feel
如果你知道一些微积分的知识
free to take this term and
你可以自己动手
try to compute a derivative yourself
算一算这个微分项
and see if you can simplify
看看你算出来的
it to the same answer that I get.
跟我得到的是不是一样
But even if you don't know calculus don't worry about it.
即使你不知道微积分 也不用担心
If you actually compute this,
如果你计算一下的话
what you get is this equation.
你会得到的是这个式子
And just write it out here.
我把它写在这里
The sum from I equals 1
将后面这个式子
through M of the,
在 i=1 到 m 上求和
essentially the error, times
其实就是预测误差
X I J. So if
乘以 x(i)j
you take this partial derivative
所以你把这个偏导数项
term and plug it back
放回到原来式子这里
in here, we can then
我们就可以将
write out our gradient descent algorithm as follows.
梯度下降算法写作如下形式
And all I've done is I
我做的就是把
took the derivative term from
前一张幻灯片中的那一行
the previous line and plugged it in there.
放到这里了
So if you have N
所以 如果你有 n 个特征
features, you would have, you know, a
也就是说
parameter vector theta, which parameters
参数向量θ 包括
theta zero, theta one, theta
θ0 θ1 θ2
two, down to theta
一直到 θn
N and you will
那么你就需要
use this update to simultaneously
用这个式子
update all of your values of theta.
来同时更新所有 θ 的值
Now if you take this
现在 如果你把这个
update rule and compare it
更新规则和我们之前
to what we were doing
用在线性回归上的
for linear regression, you might
进行比较的话
be surprised to realize that,
你会惊讶地发现
well, this equation was exactly
这个式子正是
what we had for linear regression.
我们用来做线性回归梯度下降的
In fact, if you look
事实上 如果你看一下
at the earlier videos and look
前面的视频
at the update rule, the
再仔细想想这个更新规则
gradient descent rule for linear
线性梯度下降规则
regression, it looked exactly
实际上跟我蓝色框里
like what I drew here inside the blue box.
写出来的式子是完全一样的
So are linear regression and
那么 线性回归和
logistic regression different algorithms or not?
逻辑回归是同一个算法吗？
Well, this is resolved by
要回答这个问题
observing that for logistic
我们要观察逻辑回归
regression, what has changed
看看发生了哪些变化
is that the definition for this hypothesis has changed.
实际上 假设的定义发生了变化
So whereas for linear regression
所以对于线性回归
we had H of X equals
假设函数是 h(x) 为
theta transpose X, now the
θ 转置乘以 x
definition of H of
而现在逻辑函数假设的定义
X has changed and is
已经发生了变化
instead now 1 over 1
现在已经变成了
plus e to the negative theta transpose X.
这样的形式
So even though the update
因此 即使更新参数的
rule looks cosmetically identical, because
规则看起来基本相同
the definition of the hypothesis
但由于假设的定义
has changed, this is actually
发生了变化 所以逻辑函数的梯度下降
not the same thing as gradient descent for linear regression.
跟线性回归的梯度下降实际上是两个完全不同的东西
In an earlier video, when
在先前的视频中
we were talking about gradient descent
当我们在谈论线性回归的
for linear regression, we had
梯度下降法时
talked about how to monitor
我们谈到了如何监控
gradient descent to make sure that it is converging.
梯度下降法以确保其收敛
I usually apply that same
我通常也把同样的方法
method to logistic regression too
用在逻辑回归中
to monitor gradient descent to make sure it's conversion correctly.
来监测梯度下降 以确保它正常收敛
And hopefully you can figure
希望你自己能想清楚
out how to apply that technique
如何把同样的方法
to logistic regression yourself.
应用到逻辑函数的梯度下降中
When implementing logistic regression with
当使用梯度下降法
gradient descent, we have
来实现逻辑回归时
all of these different parameter
我们有这些不同的参数 θ
values, you know, theta
就是 θ0 到 θn
0 down to theta N that we need to update using this expression.
我们需要用这个表达式来更新这些参数
And one thing we could do is have a for loop.
我们还可以使用 for 循环来实现
So for I equals 0 to
所以 for i=1 to n
N of i equals 1 to N plus 1.
或者 for i=1 to n+1
So update each of these parameter values in turn.
用一个 for 循环来更新这些参数值
But of course, rather than using
当然 不用 for 循环也是可以的
a folder, ideally we would
理想情况下
also use a vectorized implementation.
我们更提倡使用向量化的实现
And so that a vectorized
因此 向量化的实现
implementation can update, you
可以把所有这些 n 个
know, all of these N plus
参数同时更新
1 parameters all in one fell swoop.
一举搞定
And to check your own
为了检查你自己的理解
understanding, you might see
是否到位
if you can figure out how
你可以自己想想
to do the vectorized implementation
应该怎么样实现这个
of this algorithm as well.
向量化的实现方法
So now you know how
好的 现在你知道如何
to implement gradient descents for logistic aggression.
实现逻辑回归的梯度下降
There was one last idea
最后还有一个
that we had talked about earlier for which was feature scaling.
我们之前在谈线性回归时讲到的特征缩放
We saw how feature scaling can
我们看到了特征缩放是如何
help gradient descents converge faster for linear regression.
提高梯度下降的收敛速度的
The idea of feature scaling also
这个特征缩放的方法
applies to gradient descent for logistic regression.
也适用于逻辑回归
And if you have features that are on very different scales.
如果你的特征范围差距很大的话
Then applying feature scaling can also
那么应用特征缩放的方法
make it, gradient descent, run
同样也可以让逻辑回归中
faster for logistic regression.
梯度下降收敛更快
So, that's it.
就是这样
You now know how to implement
现在你知道如何实现
logistic regression, and this
逻辑回归
is a very powerful and
这是一种非常强大
probably even most widely used
甚至可能世界上使用最广泛的
classification algorithm in the world.
一种分类算法
And you now know how we get to work with yourself.
而现在你已经知道如何去实现它了